Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE
José Arcadio.
I don't know what you're doing.
but we have to talk.
I'm designing a solar weapon.
A what?
A weapon that uses sunlight.
Look at the design.
It doesn't need gunpowder. Úrsula.
It's a marvelous idea.
- Marvelous for whom?
- Any army.
If I'm able to make a functioning model.
I could sell it to the government.
I really hope that one day
you can sell these great ideas
that only you understand.
The simple village of yesteryear
had become an active town
with stores and workshops.
where one day. the slipped-clad Arabs
with rings in their ears would arrive.
- Matilde!
- I'm coming.
- Morning.
- Hello.
They're ready.
I reckon he can get
one more year out of them.
But tell José Arcadio
to quit growing so fast.
Here.
Come on. It's all right.
Thank you.
I brought candies for you and the kids.
Thanks. Put them over there.
Hey. these are delicious.
I mean it. Úrsula. You should sell them.
Oh. Matilde.
with everything else I have to do.
Think about it.
The gypsies returned in March.
Fascinating.
You are a true inventor.
I thought I'd never see you again.
The world is a big place. José Arcadio.
Traversing it takes time.
Believe me. part of my plan
was to see you again.
But show me. Teach me.
Úrsula doesn't want me
to mention this in front of our kids...
but I came to the conclusion
that the world is round. like an orange.
Do you think I'm crazy too?
Quite the contrary. my friend.
I always knew you were truly enlightened.
That's why I brought you something.
As proof of his admiration.
that very noon. Melquiades gave
José Arcadio Buendía a gift
that would have a profound influence
on the future of the village.
Aureliano! Tell your dad
I'm going to the market.
- Dad. Mom sent me to tell...
- Get out.
What's all this?
This? This is alchemy.
- Alchemy?
- The oldest science in history.
We're going to set up a laboratory
so you can experiment with the elements.
What elements?
The ones that make up
the matter of the world.
Ammonia. Lead. Mercury.
Sulfur.
Alchemy. my friend.
is the mastery of matter
and the most splendid and grandiose power
that a human being can wield.
Beyond this.
there's only God.
Aureliano!
Aureliano. come here!
While José Arcadio Buendía
devoted himself to alchemy.
Úrsula established
a marvelous candy animal business.
They were sold twice a day.
skewered on sticks of balsa wood.
- Put up the flavor sign.
- Candies!
Hey. Where is José Arcadio?
Those who had known José Arcadio Buendía
since the foundation of Macondo
were startled at how much he had changed
under Melquiades' influence.
Every alchemist
strives to unlock the mysteries of matter.
and the greatest proof of his mastery...
is transforming
base metals...
into gold.
That's not possible.
If it were that easy.
everybody would be doing it.
It is possible.
It's possible for an alchemist.
Look.
It requires a lot of skill and practice.
so I suggest
you start with something simpler.
TRANSMUTING METALS
THE DOUBLING OF GOLD
...because the idea of doubling
is fascinating to me.
Úrsula. Melquiades is staying to eat.
Eat what you can.
What you see is what there is.
Don't worry. thank you.
I need to get going.
They're waiting for me at the camp.
Ma'am.
Melquiades. tonight I'll start...
See you tomorrow.
I'm afraid that won't be possible.
We're packing up.
We leave at dawn.
But we just started the experiments.
I know.
but you have all you need to continue.
You don't need me.
But don't worry.
I promise I'll be back. my friend.
If you invite friends to eat.
ask first if we have enough to share.
You live in your own world.
locked up in that office.
Just so you know.
it's an alchemical laboratory.
And you know what...
it'll make us rich.
It's about time.
The inheritance from my dad
is running out.
José Arcadio Buendía.
get that gypsy's ideas out of your head.
We have a family to feed.
José Arcadio. Aureliano. Breakfast.
Have you seen the kids?
No.
It's going that way!
Go that way. Aureliano! Run.
Pilar. have you seen my kids?
They left early and aren't back yet.
They must be around somewhere.
Don't worry. Since you're here.
how about I read your cards?
Ask away.
José Arcadio Buendía.
Draw.
He sees the world differently.
He's a man of passions and obsessions.
Be thankful
they're neither women nor other vices.
or he'd be drunk
at Catarino's all the time.
They're going to get an earful.
We'll finish up later. Thank you.
José Arcadio.
Aureliano!
TRANSMUTING METALS
THE DOUBLING OF GOLD
The boys showed up.
You'll never guess what they have.
Tell me you didn't take the coins.
Where are they?
I followed the formula step-by-step.
What formula?
A scientific process to double gold.
Does that blob look like gold to you?
Maybe I could separate it.
I'd have to use
a little more sulfur. less lead.
How could you do that without asking me?
Those coins are for my candy business.
What business?
On top of not doing anything
for this family.
you have the nerve
to destroy the little we have left.
I'm going to get back every gram of gold.
I promise.
No. I don't need you to get the gold back.
I need you to take care of your family.
of your kids.
who have been abandoned to God's mercy.
They look like savages. Look at them.
José Arcadio.
Aureliano.
Come here.
Come in.
From that evening on. José Arcadio Buendía
gave them his best hours.
- He taught them how to read and write.
- Be patient.
- He explained the marvels of the world...
- I've got one!
...pushing the limits of their imaginations
to incredible extremes.
That was how the boys learned
that it was possible
to cross the Aegean Sea on foot...
...in Southern Africa...
...island hopping
to the port of Thessaloniki.
...their only pastime was to sit and think.
Don't even think about it.
These are ready to sell.
I'll tell José Arcadio to get ready.
I counted them
in case you thought about being naughty.
One morning. Úrsula came into the room
and experienced a confusing feeling
of shame at the sight of her son.
so well-equipped for life
that it seemed abnormal to her.
And she relived her newlywed terrors.
What's that face for?
You look like you saw
Prudencio Aguilar's ghost.
I saw something worse.
What could be worse than that?
José Arcadio.
I just saw him naked.
So?
He has a huge member.
Úrsula. that's normal.
He's growing.
Everything develops at the same time.
That's not normal. Pilar.
It looks like a deformity.
It's worse than a pig's tail.
Maybe I condemned him to be alone forever.
Quite the contrary.
He'll be happy.
But if it brings you peace.
I can read his future.
Yes. please.
Cut it.
Relax. José Arcadio. It won't hurt.
Draw three.
What do they say?
That you will be indomitable. like a gale.
Good heavens.
José Arcadio felt like his bones
were filling up with foam.
He experienced a languid fear
and a terrible desire to weep.
Well. what did the cards say?
He won't suffer for women or offspring.
I promise.
During the frightful time
of laying awake that night.
he desired Pilar Ternera again
with brutal anxiety.
He wanted to be with her...
for them to have never left the granary.
and for her to say. "Good heavens!"
Wednesday...
Pilar Ternera
had allowed him to understand
why men fear death.
- Morning.
- Morning. What flavors do you have?
- Tamarind. corozo. lime. and orange.
- Orange and corozo. please.
Okay.
- Oh. my dear.
- Pilar.
Is business good?
We can barely keep up.
Stay with the kids.
- I'll go get more candy from home.
- Sure. go.
- Lime and corozo. please.
- Grab them.
- An orange one.
- The orange ones are delicious.
José Arcadio. give me the candy.
Where were you?
This isn't the first night
you've snuck out.
You're not going to tell me?
I met a woman.
A woman? What were you doing with a woman?
More like. what was she doing with me?
She has a body that smells of smoke...
and her laughter scares the doves away.
When she touches me.
it's like she knows my body
better than I do.
If only you knew
the things a tongue can do. Aureliano.
You'd be surprised.
And there comes a moment
when we almost collapse in pleasure.
What does it feel like?
Like an earthquake.
The sunbeams converge in the lens.
so the target starts to burn.
By focusing on just one point.
the sunbeams could burn the target.
- That's it!
- Mom!
Did you see that. Úrsula?
We did it.
It does work.
Many years later.
before an army officer
gave the command to fire.
Colonel Aureliano Buendía
relived that warm March afternoon
when his father interrupted his lesson.
and he heard the gypsies
returning to the village.
Melquiades.
Come!
Come closer.
See the latest discovery
from the sages of Memphis!
The wonder that belonged to King Solomon.
Thirty reales.
The chest gave off a glacial exhalation.
There was an enormous.
transparent block inside.
with infinite internal needles
in which the light of the sunset
was broken up into colored stars.
The largest diamond in the world.
No. sir.
That's ice.
This is the great invention of our time.
Five reales if you want to touch it.
It's boiling.
THE MAGNIFICENT WONDERS
OF THE SAGES OF MEMPHIS
See the power of the Sumerian formula.
which has remained hidden for centuries.
THE RENOWNED EUCLID
The syrup
that makes you
invisible.
I'm sorry. sir.
Do you know Melquiades. the alchemist?
Melquiades perished
on the sandbanks of Singapore.
That can't be true. Melquiades must be...
Melquiades died.
The best way to pay my respects
is by not letting alchemy die.
José Arcadio.
José Arcadio...
One Thursday in January.
at two o'clock in the morning.
Amaranta was born.
Úrsula examined her carefully.
She was light and watery. like a newt.
but all her parts were human.
- She's so beautiful.
- You wanted a daughter so badly.
She hasn't cried yet.
She's a very calm girl.
- Yes. congrats.
- Hey. this cookie is great.
They're from Carmen's.
Try the bread.
I made this honey bread myself.
Hey. where's the man?
He must be in the workshop.
- I want to hold her.
- He'll be here soon.
We did it! Úrsula!
- Mom!
- Úrsula!
We have guests.
The king of the mountain.
Yeah. because he was gonna die up there.
Friend. Magnífico. Gerineldo.
You are looking at gold coins.
Recovered from an impossible alloy.
Is this real?
Yes.
You have no idea how happy that makes me.
- Congrats.
- How many goats is that?
Let's talk business.
My boy. what do you think?
It looks like dog shit.
Watch your mouth!
Let's celebrate.
- Yes.
- A drink.
- Beautiful.
- Yes.
What a lovely little hand you have.
Come in. My brothers aren't home.
He humiliates me!
He still treats me like a little boy.
Don't get so worked up
over such stupid things.
I won't lock myself up
in that laboratory again.
I'll live life my own way.
Calm down.
So why don't you tell your dad
what you want to do?
What I want
is to be with you.
Me too.
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN THE AMERICAS
THE MAGIC CARPET
Look!
This pales in comparison
to how I feel when we're together.
Now you are a man.
You're going to have a son.
SHOWS
What's wrong?
Nothing.
José Arcadio.
Let me sleep!
José Arcadio lost his appetite.
and he could not sleep.
It was so bad that. bitten by
a virulent rancor against the world.
he left his bed one night
to mingle in the tumult of the fair
and find some solace there.
After wandering about
among all kinds of contraptions.
he spotted a very young gypsy girl.
The most beautiful woman
he had ever seen in his life.
Upon first contact.
the bones of the girl seemed to become
disjointed with a disorderly crunch.
like the sound of a box of dominoes.
Come on. kids. Wake up.
Where's your brother?
He hasn't come back.
Matilde.
Have you seen my son?
No.
I last saw him at your house.
Let's go ask Pilar.
Pilar!
Have you seen José Arcadio?
Catarino!
- Catarino. have you seen my son?
- Your son? No.
I saw him last night with the gypsies.
He's become a gypsy.
Go. Go home.
Tell your dad.
In a few hours. José Arcadio Buendía
gathered a group of well-equipped men.
After three days
of useless searching... they returned.
For several weeks.
José Arcadio Buendía let himself
be overcome with consternation.
Silver works better in filaments.
You'll see.
Don't worry.
Your brother will be back.
Come on.
Grab the hammer.
You have to hammer the silver into shape.
From below.
Time put things in their place.
Dad?
The basket!
- Dad!
- Those are the properties of matter.
Nothing extraordinary
if you understand it.
During his imprisonment.
José Arcadio Buendía
begged in the depth of his heart
that the miracle
wasn't turning metals into gold
but Úrsula's return.
Dad! Look at that.
Five months later. Úrsula returned.
It's your mom. Go.
She came from the other side
of the great swamp.
where there were towns
that received mail every month
and were familiar with good living.
Where's José Arcadio?
I never found the gypsies.
And no one knew anything about him.
Look.
She's beautiful.
Who are all these people?
They all wanted to see
the wonder of this town
in the middle of the great swamp.
You did it.
You found the paths
that connect Macondo to the world.
I want to introduce you
to Visitación and Cataure.
They accompanied me during the trip.
They're going to live with us.
Welcome.
Sir. how are you?
How are you. sir?
Welcome.
Be careful.
Don't ever leave again.
You neither.
Pilar.
What are you doing here?
Whose baby is that?
It's mine.
A little boy.
Who's the father?
José Arcadio.
I'm here to give him to you.
You must be joking.
We fell in love. Úrsula.
There's no way.
But we did.
There. there. sweetie.
It was you.
You were the one
who made my son disappear.
If you manipulated him with
your witchcraft and created that child.
raise that bastard alone yourself.
Look at him.
Look. Úrsula. He's your flesh and blood.
He has our parents' faces.
There. there...
If he's a Buendía.
he needs to grow up with his family.
Fine. I will take that child.
So long as that whore
never steps inside this house again.
He'll never know who birthed him
because what she did
disgraced this family.
Those are the terms. Pilar.
He'll be better off here.
The baby was given the name José Arcadio.
but they called him Arcadio
to avoid confusion.
Aureliano spent interminable hours
in the laboratory.
learning the art of silverwork
by his own experimentation.
Adolescence had taken away
the softness of his voice.
He became silent
and solitary.
But it had restored the intense expression
that he had in his eyes when he was born.
Let's play!
Come on.
Go hide!
What's that?
Run!
- Run!
Go hide.
Run.
What's that?
Arcadio. Amaranta.
Stop speaking Wayuu.
I told you to speak Spanish.
What's with you?
Someone is coming.
BASED ON THE NOVEL
BY GABRIEL GARCÍA MÁRQUEZ
Subtitle translation by: Alison Woods
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org